Guy Louden is an Australian artist and curator. From 2014 to 2016, Louden was a director of Moana Project Space, the leading artist-run gallery in Perth. In 2015, he co-founded and managed Success, a large-scale art space in Fremantle. He has curated exhibitions for the Perth International Arts Festival, Moana, and Success. Since 2017 he has also exhibited his own art. Louden holds a MA in Art History from the University of Manchester (2013), and a Master of Art Curating from the University of Sydney (2018).

# Major Projects

2017-19 — Curator and Artist in *Preppers* 

A series of related art exhibitions appearing at galleries across the country, including Firstdraft, Bus Projects, and Polizia, and culminating in a major show at Fremantle Arts Centre. Core artists are Loren Kronemyer, Dan McCabe, and Guy Louden.

2016 — Curator of No Confidence

A large-scale exhibition of audio-visual art from celebrated international artists, examining today's political situation through cutting-edge contemporary art. Presented at Success, it was a headlining event in the Perth International Arts Festival.

2016 — Founder/Program Manager, Success

Co-founder of Success, a new contemporary art gallery and exhibition programme. Success transformed the abandoned basement level of a former MYER store into an enormous art venue. Following a 9 month period of redevelopment, the venue opened in February 2016. Louden continued at Success as Program Manager and also curator-at-large.

2015 — Curator of Theatres

A show exploring geopolitical conflict, as a head-lining exhibition in the 2015 Perth International Arts Festival. Presented across an entire wing of the WA Museum, it contained the work of peak-career international artists and received wide critical praise. Artists included Venice Biennale participants and Prix Marcel Duchamp winners such as Richard Mosse, Cyprien Gaillard, and Laurent Grasso, among others.

2015 — Curator of Specific Gravity

A visual arts exhibition at Moana Project Space, Perth. Specific Gravity exhibited work from artists across Australia. Artists explored the complex interdependencies of substance in natural phenom-ena and history.

2014-16 — Director of Moana Project Space

Moana Project Space was a custom built whitewall ARI gallery in a heritage building in Perth CBD. Moana is WA's most prominent artist-run gallery. Between 2012 and 2018, it showed emerging artists alongside leading national and international artists.

#### Education

Master of Art Curating, University of Sydney, 2018.

Average 87.4% with 1 result pending.

Master of Arts (Art History), University of Manchester, 2012-13.

Bachelor of Arts (Fine Arts, English), University of Western Australia, 2008-11.

Study abroad scholarship UCLA.

# Professional Experience

2018- Art Install Technician, Carriageworks, Sydney.

2018, Curatorial Internship, Artbank, Sydney.

2017, Artist Officer and Gallery Assistant, Warakurna Artists, Ngaanyatjarra-Giles.

2016, 2019, Art Technician, Wesfarmers Collection, Perth.

2016, Artist Field Officer, Martumili Arts, Eastern Pilbara region.

2015-16, Co-Founder and Program Manager, Success, Fremantle.

2014-17, Co-Director, Moana Project Space, Perth.

## Selected Exhibitions & Publications

2019, Catalogue essay, *Post-Leisure*, Outer Space gallery, Brisbane.

2019, Artist and Producer, *Preppers*, Fremantle Arts Centre, Fremantle.

2019, Artist, *Network Archeology*, Cool Change Contemporary, Perth.

2018, Artist, WROL, Bus Projects, Melbourne.

2017, Curator and Artist, *SHTF*, Firstdraft, Sydney.

2017, Curator, Artist, *Nature Kit*, ArtTra festival, Perth

2016, Curator, *No Confidence*, Perth International Arts Festival, Perth.

2016, Exhibition Exegesis, *No Confidence: PIAF Visual Arts Guide*, Perth.

2015, Co-Curator, *Theatres*, Perth International Arts Festival, Perth.

2015, Curator, *Specific Gravity*, Moana Project Space, Perth.

2015, Catalogue Essay, *Khazi: Lilly Kaiser*, Moana Project Space, Perth.

2015, Exhibition Exegesis, *Theatres: Perth International Arts Festival Guide*, Perth. 2014, Essay, *Hyperborea*, Free Range, Perth.

2013, Catalogue Essay, *Warning: Simon Finn*, Moana Project Space, Perth.

#### Referees

Dr Oliver Watts, Head Curator, Artbank

Prof Ted Snell, Chief Cultural Officer, UWA

Kri Leitner, Director - Program and Production, Carriageworks

#### Links

Personal website, <u>quylouden.com</u>

Curation example, <u>guylouden.com/no-confidence</u>

Writing sample, <u>guylouden.com/data/network-archeology-fiction</u>

Artwork examples, <u>guylouden.com/data/past-work-images</u>

Success gallery, success.gallery